Guide to the Lance Loud and Loud Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lance Loud and Loud family papers
1957-2013
GEN MSS 1320
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
13.31
(40 boxes)
Loud, Lance, 1951-2001
Loud family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Patricia L. Loud on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 26-28 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 29: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 37 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Loud family
The Loud family was the subject of the documentary television series An American Family, which aired on PBS in 1973 and is often described as the first American reality television show. The show featured parents Pat and Bill Loud and their children Lance, Kevin, Grant, Delilah, and Michelle.
Lance Loud
Lance Loud (1951-2001) was the eldest son of the Loud family, which was the subject of the documentary television series An American Family. He was a focal point of the series in part because he announced his homosexuality during the filming of the show. Loud's band, The Mumps, were regular performers in the downtown New York City punk scene in the 1970s. He remained a fixture of the New York and Los Angeles social scenes and worked as a freelance journalist, often working with Details magazine.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, photographs, printed material, and audiovisual materials documenting the lives of Lance Loud and the Loud family. Lance Loud papers consist of correspondence, personal papers, personal objects including Loud's professional and personal contact files, clippings, and other papers and include materials relating to his band The Mumps. Loud family papers document their involvement in the television documentary An American Family, its reception and subsequent followups, and the 2011 television movie Cinema Verite based on the series. Photographs consist of family pictures. Audiovisual materials include home videos, tributes to Lance Loud, audiorecordings of The Mumps, and videorecordings of television programs related to An American Family.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Lance Loud Papers, 1972-2012. II. Loud Family Papers, 1972-2011. III. Photographs, 1957-2000. IV. Printed Material, 1977-2013. V. Audiovisual Materials, 1989-2011.
American family; Reality television programs -- United States; Documentary television programs -- United States; Musicians -- United States; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Musicians -- United States -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; Loud, Lance, 1951-2001; Loud family; Loud, Pat, 1926-; Mumps (Musical group); Public Broadcasting Service (U.S.)
- Lance Loud papers, 1972-2012; Series I; 4.97; (13 boxes)
  - Piercing fans mag, etc., undated (Box 1)
  - Lance's fan mail for his writing & mail from friends, fans, Clive Davis, 1973-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Concrete Blonde, undated (Box 1)
  - Contracts, circa 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - Cockettes, undated (Box 1)
  - Castro, Rick, undated (Box 1)
  - Angie Bowie, undated (Box 1)
  - Marty Schwartz, undated (Box 1)
  - Sin Brothers (Sit & Spin), undated (Box 1)
  - Sparks, undated (Box 1)
  - Cree Summer, undated (Box 1)
  - Kristian Hoffman, undated (Box 1)
  - Hard Rock Cafe, undated (Box 1)
  - William Shockley, undated (Box 1)
  - Spano, Vincent, undated (Box 1)
  - Edith Massey, undated (Box 1)
  - Munro/Hawes, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Michael Musto, undated (Box 1)
  - Steven Kutchen (Arachnaphobia), undated (Box 1)
  - Nina Jackson, undated (Box 1)
  - Bottom, Roddy, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972, 1995, undated (Box 1)
  - Gholson, Craig, 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - Fiorillo, Elisa, undated (Box 2)
  - Leslie Dowdall, undated (Box 2)
  - DeMornay, Rebecca, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Dreamchild, 1985 (Box 2)
  - European masters clips, undated (Box 2)
  - Len Prince, undated (Box 2)
  - Rock 'n' Role-playing a history of rock page 106, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Lina Santiago, undated (Box 2)
  - Whoopi Goldberg, undated (Box 2)
  - Styles Caldwell, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Douglas Beane, undated (Box 2)
  - Auction "One from the heart", undated (Box 2)
  - Abba, undated (Box 2)
  - Addams Family (interview with Raoul Julia, etc., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Lypsinka, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Peeples Nia, undated (Box 2)
  - Petit Bon Bons, 1973, undated (Box 2)
  - Vickie Galvez, undated (Box 2)
  - Philadelphia, undated (Box 3)
  - Gregory Poe, undated (Box 3)
  - "Pat"-the movie, undated (Box 3)
  - Roddy Bottom (band), 1993 (Box 3)
  - Rickie Lee Jones, n.y. June (Box 3)
  - Lisa Eliot, undated (Box 3)
  - Millionaire, undated (Box 3)
  - Ann Magnuson, undated (Box 3)
  - Debi Mazar, 1991 August 15 (Box 3)
  - Christophr Makos, undated (Box 3)
  - Marriage-Made for TV Marriage, undated (Box 3)
  - Norman Fisher [Empty folder] (Box 3)
  - Faye Dunaway [Empty folder] (Box 3)
  - Max's interviews #1, undated (Box 3)
  - Max's interviews II, undated (Box 3)
  - Max's interviews III, undated (Box 3)
  - Mumps, 1981, 1993, undated (Box 3)
  - Make-up (various interviews), 1990 August 15 (Box 3)
  - Bird show, undated (Box 3)
  - ? Possible orig. play w/autograph handwritten copy, undated (Box 3)
  - Arnold Schwarzenegger interview, 1990 August 15 (Box 3)
  - Lance pay stubs, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Carrie zines, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Jackie Harner, undated (Box 3)
  - John Fleck, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-2003, undated (Box 4)
  - Personal papers, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Lance Loud tribute, 2002; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Separated Materials
    2 CD-Rs, labelled "Lance's Memorial," removed to Box 37, restricted fragile electronic media.
  - Correspondence with friends, circa 1990 (Box 5)
  - Education, 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - Guitar lessons, undated (Box 5)
  - Xeroxes of letters Lance wrote to Andy, undated (Box 5)
  - Towards the end, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Calendar, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Notebook-research, undated (Box 6)
  - Notebook-research, undated (Box 6)
  - Life calendar, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Calendar, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Calendar, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Business cards, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Extreme medical emergency, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Exciting lives-vol. 1, undated (Box 7)
  - Mumps promotional material and press, 1975-1980 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983-2000 (Box 7)
  - Mumps, undated (Box 7)
  - Mumps, undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981, undated (Box 7)
  - Loud, Kevin, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Press clippings, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Press clippings, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Lance birth and death, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Lance birth and death, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Lance Loud, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Lance Loud, 2001-2002 (Box 10)
  - Part of Lance Out Loud book proposal, 2012 (Box 10)
  - Artwork, 1982, undated (Box 34)
  - Cigarette case, undated (Box 36)
  - Keys, undated (Box 36)
  - Wallet, undated (Box 36)
  - Rolodex A-L, undated (Box 38)
  - Rolodex M-Z, undated (Box 39)
- Loud family papers, 1972-2011; Series II; 2.75; (8 boxes)
  - Crosstalk interview tape, 1972 March 30 (Box 11)
  - Questions for the Louds, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Printed material, 1996-2009 (Box 11)
  - Loud family press, circa 2000-2003 (Box 11)
  - Loud family press, 1990, undated (Box 11)
  - Loud family press, 1996-2002 (Box 11)
  - Loud family film, 2002 (Box 11)
  - Loud family fan mail, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Loud family fan mail, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Loud family fan mail, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Loud family fan mail, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Loud family press, 1995-2003, undated (Box 12)
  - American Family press kit, 1982, 2013 (Box 12)
  - American Family theatrical project, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mom's 70th birthday, 1996 October (Box 12)
  - Printed material, circa 2002-2006 (Box 13)
  - Loud family press, 1973-2001 (Box 13)
  - American Family clippings, 1973-2002 (Box 13)
  - Printed material, 1993-2011 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 2000-2003 (Box 13)
  - An American Family, undated (Box 13)
  - Press clippings, 2002-2003 (Box 14)
  - An American Family, circa 1982-2010 (Box 15)
  - An American Family, circa 1975-2007 (Box 15)
  - Original AM Family press kit, undated (Box 15)
  - Living out Loud, undated (Box 15)
  - Living out Loud, undated (Box 40)
  - An American Family, 1973, undated (Box 16)
  - An American Family, 1993-2002 (Box 16)
  - HBO/Cinema Verite, 2010 August (Box 17)
  - An American Family revisited: correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
- Photographs, 1957-2000; Series III; 3.26; (12 boxes)
  - Photographs, 1972-2000, undated (Box 18)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 19)
  - Glass frame with adhered photographs (Box 29)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Dick Cavett show, undated (Box 30)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 30)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 20)
  - Photograph album, 1996 (Box 20)
  - Photograph album, 1978 (Box 21)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 22)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 22)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 22)
  - Photograph album, 1996 July (Box 22)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 23)
  - Photograph album, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Photograph album: Mumps, undated (Box 23)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 31)
  - Photograph album, 1957-1958, undated (Box 32)
  - Photograph album, undated (Box 33)
  - Photograph album, 1990 (Box 34)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 23)
- Printed materials, 1977-2013; Series IV; 0.88; (3 boxes)
  - Magazines, 1977-2004 (Box 24)
  - Lance Out Loud, 2012 (Box 24)
  - Magazines, 1961-1997 (Box 25)
  - Clippings and newspapers, 1981-2001, undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Newspapers and magazines, 1992-2013 (Box 35)
- Audiovisual materials, 1989-2011; Series V; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Lance Loud! A death in An American Family: videocassette, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Lance Loud! A death in An American Family: videocassette, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Looseleaf report #55 Lance Loud: videocassette, 1989 August 10 (Box 26)
  - Videocassette, undated (Box 26)
  - Videocassette, undated (Box 27)
  - Videocassette, undated (Box 27)
  - Thanksgiving: Video8 cassette, 1992 (Box 27)
  - Loud/Thanksgiving (Houston): Video9 cassette, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Video8 cassette, undated (Box 27)
  - Cinema Verite: DVD, 2011 (Box 27)
  - Video8 cassette, undated (Box 28)
  - Hoffman, Kristian: The Am Fam variations: CD, undated (Box 28)
  - Mumps: How I saved the world: CD, 2005 (Box 28)